One on the pipeline, if I may.
I wonder if you could just update us on your thoughts on the confidence and potential for
abalacimab.
And also, I see that it's still showing us a 2027 readout milestone in the slide deck.
Clinical trials is now showing a late December 27 primary completion.
So is that still a 2027 out event, or is the potential for slippage into 2027?
Thanks so much.
Yeah, thanks, Simon.
So we remain excited about abalacimab.
As a reminder, this is a monthly monoclonal antibody that has shown outstanding, I think,
overall pharmacokinetic pharmacodynamics on very well-behaved antibody on factor XI.
We've seen with competitor data that factor XI appears to deliver on the promise of very
strong anticoagulation without increased bleeding risk, which is what the genetics would indicate
for us.
And so we have the study ongoing in patients who are ineligible for NOACs.
And that study, we have upsized that study given the event rates that we saw.
So you can also see that at clinicaltrials.gov.
But we're on track for a readout before the end of the year.
That is a readout at 75% of events, just to be clear.
And then the study would continue if it's not successful at that point, or that doesn't
meet the stopping criteria.
At that point, to finish the number of events in 2028.
And then we evaluate now, or are in the process of beginning additional studies in secondary
stroke prevention, as well as assessing other indications as well.
So excited about that opportunity.
We think it could be a significant asset if the trials ultimately read out positive.
Great.
Thanks so much.
Thank you.
Your next question comes from the line of TiVo Bothering from Morgan Stanley.
Please go ahead.
Thank you.
Just a question on Hidvisma.
I know that you have launched the drug and we start to see the cells coming in.
Do you have any more visibility on what you expect to be the shape of the bolus of cells
from this therapy over the next few years?
If you have any indication on when you expect the cells to peak?
You know, is it next year?
Is it 2028?
And then on the magnitude, I think in the past Novartis was talking about multi-billion
dollars for this asset.
So just to clarify, is it 2028?
Is it 2028?
And then on the magnitude, I think in the past Novartis was talking about multi-billion
dollars for this asset.